## Macy Ma - Front-End Developer

- Name: Macy Ma

- Title: Senior Front-End Developer- Email: macyma18@gmail.com

- Visa Status: Work visa

Able to build a whole application from translating requirements to actionable, specific, technical tasks; coding and manage progress. I used to work at Alibaba Group (co-founder Jack Ma) for three years and my title is Senior Front-End Engineer.

#### **Skills**

- Programming: JavaScript (ES6+) / HTML5 / CSS3
- Library & Framework: React / Next.js / jQuery
- Design: Common Design Principles / Sketch / PhotoShop / Responsive Web Design
- Tooling: VSCode / Git (GitFlow) / webpack / Babel / Debug (Devtools) / SASS / Less
- Industry: e-HR and Recruitment / Internationalization

## Work experience

### Front-End Developer/Freelance (Gap Year) - Jun. 2018 - Sep. 2019

- Traveled.
- Learned English.
- Prepared to immigrate to New Zealand.
- Did a part-time remote job, completed two projects.

## Alibaba Group Holding Limited (<a href="https://www.alibabagroup.com/">https://www.alibabagroup.com/</a>)

Alibaba Group (co-founder Jack Ma) has more than 101,958 full-time employees, like FLAG Companies, only the best of the best in China can join in Alibaba.

I was in the Information Platform Business Unit-User experience Department of Alibaba (now renamed Enterprise Intelligence Department), and I worked as a Front-End Engineer to handle the requirements of Alibaba Recruitment Business from October 2014 to June 2018. Alibaba Recruitment Business includes more than 12 systems serving all Alibaba staff and target candidates.

#### Senior Front-End Engineer / Aug. 2017 - Jun. 2018

- Led three outsourced employees to start the recruitment internationalization project, completed the internationalization of the Recruitment Workbench System and <u>Overseas Recruitment Official Platform</u>. Made a foundation for the company's internationalization.
- Rebuild the Internal Transfer System.

#### Front-End Engineer / Jul. 2015 - Aug. 2017

- Mainly created the Recruitment Workbench System which is a recruitment management platform. I completed this project from architecture design to coding to release.
- Maintained several uxcore components (<u>uxcore</u> is an open-source react component lib for PC, belongs our team) and started to learn to write unit test.
- Other projects: rebuild the Talent Pool System which is a system that the team leader can find target candidates, and completed the structure interview feature.
- All of these projects use React, Reflux and uxcore lib.

## Front-End Intern / Oct. 2014 - May. 2015

- Participated in building the Focus System which is a campus interview system, included Face-to-Face Interview, Telephone Interview, and Video Interview. The type of remote interview saves company might 1+ million NZD per year.
- This project uses jQuery, Backbone and Node.js.
- Familiar with the team's development process, project structure, and business.

## **Open Source Project**

- <u>uxcore</u> participant. React component lib for PC. I have maintained several components and wrote the unit test.
- <u>the-javascript/structure</u> partner. Put JavaScript related knowledge in a structural way. Help people learn and verify the skills. I finished some parts of front-end and wrote several documents.

#### Education

Dalian Minzu University, Network Engineering — Bachelor, 2011 - 2015

# Links

- GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/MacyMa18">https://github.com/MacyMa18</a>

- LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/macy-ma-107887134/

- My Page: <a href="http://macyma.me/">http://macyma.me/</a>